<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on English Version</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on English Version</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>es-es</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Two examples of iteration with purrr - Class for the R-Studio certification</title>
      <link>/2020/06/two-examples-of-iteration-with-purrr.en-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/06/two-examples-of-iteration-with-purrr.en-us/</guid>
      <description>CertificationI recently became certified as a R-Studio Tidyverse instructor. To pass the certification there are two exams, one of Tidyverse or Shiny and other of teaching.In this blog I am going to share a 15 minute class that I prepared to as parto of the teaching exam.
What to teach about?I use loops frecquently in for my work. I decided to look for two specific examples of functions in purrr package that could be motivating for the students.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipe for your first interactive tutorial</title>
      <link>/2020/03/cooking-your-first-tutorial.en-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/03/cooking-your-first-tutorial.en-us/</guid>
      <description>The aim of this post is to provide a route map highlighting the resources available to generate your own tutorial.
HelloLast year I helped to transform some courses from a DataCamp format to Ines Montani framework. Here you have some examples of tutorials created with this framework.
After one busy year that included the end of my PhD finally I have some time to make a contribution to the community about how to build these tutorials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where to publish your Shiny App?</title>
      <link>/2020/03/where-to-publish-your-shinyapp.en-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/03/where-to-publish-your-shinyapp.en-us/</guid>
      <description>MotivationI started to develop Shiny Apps because of my research. The development of a Shiny App for the analysis of toxicological databases allowed me to explore the data in relation to different criteria.
Where to publish?After finishing the app, my first question was whether to publish the Shiny App. Should I include it as supplementary material of other paper or could be published as software itself?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interactive web applications with Shiny - meetup material</title>
      <link>/2020/02/intro_shiny.en-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/02/intro_shiny.en-us/</guid>
      <description>Hello!In February I will participate in a meetup of the R-Ladies chapter R-Ladies Resistencia-Corrientes and the R user group R en el NEA. These groups represent the R users of Resistencia and Corrientes cities of Argentina.
The meetup consists of a workshop where attendees will learn to build their own apps. This material improves the one that I presented in an R-Ladies Buenos Aires meetup in 2017.
MaterialSlides</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>